,
, and I think she was used by the doctors in multiple times many times to dump the
credentials to export the credentials to modify the registry keys. So many of them have a, don't know about the Windows registry. So if you go for a registry editor, so in the registry editor there's some of the registry keys like HKLM, local machine HK, current users and all.
So this is a database, okay? This is basically we will call it a Windows database. So this database will contain some information like some configuration files and some application configuration files and the background, so which backgrounds the Windows needs to load and the credentials gives a name password.
So when you try to login into the machine, so your username and password will be validated by the registry, by this registry keys, okay?
So instead of the registry keys, it will be going to validate your Windows user name and passwords, whether it was correct or not. So like that, it is a certain database, so how was the Windows Defender antivirals?
Some antivirals are registry keys and whether your Windows different was active or inactive, whether it was disabled or Windows different or other, it's inactive, so every information will be hidden inside the registry, okay?
So that the threat factor will be mostly using the registry key to do some stuff, do some task while they're doing, while they're doing the Septemberical time attacks, okay?
So we are using a ridge.exe in a lot, a lot and a lot in our course, so don't worry about that.
Let's see here you can see the SAM and security eyes. This both keys will be, both of the keys will be storing the information about the username and password, has a siege and everything, okay?
So every user will be, every user username and password will be saved inside both of the key.
And we have another set of keys also, if you go to the software, so you can see the Amazon Notepad.exe and Microsoft, so this is a small database for every application which is inside the machine, so it will store the information, it will store the configuration center, okay?
So let's, we can do, we can do many attacks, many task integers, but in this video, I'm just going to dump one of the keys, so here you can see, here you can see one command, dumbcrunchl size, SAM system and security type, okay?
So D will dump this keys, okay? Let's get on to and we'll dump this key. Let's go to the, we'll save it in a C, okay? Let's save it in a C.
Don't, no need of for this, and let's save these things in a, before that.
So now you can see the access of the deny, because I was in the user revelation, okay? Where am I slash all?
So you can see my privilege was a medium mandatory level, so I was in the local account and member of an administrative group, no problem.
So if you do not have enough understanding about the privilege escalation, we will, we will have a separate section for a privilege escalation. Let's open a command.
So let's copy the command, sometimes you can't able to copy that, just you control C and paste it here.
So now you can see the operations completed successfully, because I have enough privilege to do that by my slash, okay? Who am?
So now you can see my privilege was a high mandatory level, but in a previous section, which was denied that has a, only a medium mandatory level of privilege, which we have.
So now our, our privilege is an high mandatory level. I just opened the open my command prompt with a written as an administrator. So now you can see the, both of both the commands, so it was written in this command was running in an administrator level privilege, so this was running in normal user privilege.
We'll do some USC bypassing state of privilege escalation, so to bypass this things, escalating privileges, okay? Let's get on to the dumb sessions, so what we dumped.
So no worry about which I have showed before, so it's just we will see everything in the privilege escalation section, so no need to worry.
So you can see because we have dumb, or three of the file, SAM system and security, so all the files are inside the few directory, okay?
So not only for this dumping the credentials, so it was used to to modify disabling Windows Defender, disabling antivirus software, disabling EDRs, okay, a lot and a lot of things will be there, okay?
So we're adding some rules inside the database and enabling the hard DB. We can see each and everything in our coming sessions, so the wordings will be might difficult if you're new to cyber security, if you're a freshers to cyber security, we can see everything in our coming sessions, so this is not advanced course.
We will learn everything one by this not advanced course first, okay? Some course will be like they will be teaching starting from the advanced.
If you do not know the counts, we can't able to understand what they are saying, but this course is not like that.
I just covered from the basics and I guess going to an advance, so this course will be most mainly focused on basics to advance.
I didn't cover about the intermediate ones, also I gone with the basics, I gone, I gone till advanced, okay?
Anyway, this course will teach you a lot and a lot of things into a cyber security, a real time attacks, real hackers, real detectors, how they will operate, how they will perform all the attacks and sit on a machine.
Let's go up to the studio and we'll continue our discussion in the next video. See you guys, bye bye.